Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Geographic Images circa 1600-2006 PR 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: New York City Views - the Bronx, 50414
  - Subseries IIA: BRONX - BOXED MATERIAL, 51884
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Street Views, 183054
      - Streets F-G, 183084 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Fenton Avenue, 183085 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Forest Avenue, 183086 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Franklin Avenue, 183087 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Grand Concourse, 183088 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Streets H-L, 183089 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Kingsbridge Road, 183090 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Streets M-O, 183091 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Melrose Avenue, 183092 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Mosholu Parkway, 183093 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Mott Avenue, 183094 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Streets P-S, 183095 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Pelham Parkway, 183096 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Pennyfield Avenue, 183097 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Prospect Avenue, 183098 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Sedgwick Avenue, 183099 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Streets T-W, 183100 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Tremont Avenue, 185175 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Waring Avenue, 185176 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Washington Avenue, 185177 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Webster Avenue, 185178 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Westchester Avenue, 185179 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - West Farms Road, 185180 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - White Plains Road, 185181 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Streets X - Z, 185182 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Numbered Avenues (includes third avenue), 185183 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - 132nd - 149th street, 185184 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 150th - 169th street, 185185 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 170th - 179th street, 185186 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 180th - 189th street, 185187 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 190th - 210th street, 185188 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 211th - 249th street, 185189 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Unidentified street scenes, 185190 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Neighborhoods, 183055
      - City Island, 185191 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Spuyten Duyvil, 185192 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Throgs Neck, 185193 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Cemeteries, 183056
      - Cemeteries (A-Z), 185194 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Parks, 185195
      - Parks (A-Z), 185196 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Bronx Park, including Botanical Gardens, Bronx Museums, 185197 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Bronx Zoological Park, 185198 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Crotona Park, 185199 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Drake Park, 185200 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Pelham Bay Park, 185201 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Van Cordlandt Park, 185202 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Buildings, 183057
      - Buildings-Churches and Synagogues, 185204 (Box 4, Folder 12-22)
      - Buildings- Clubs and Organizations, 183062 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Government-General, 185216 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Government-Fire Houses, 185217 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Hotels A-Z, 185218 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
      - Buildings-Institutions- HospitalsA-Z, 185221 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Shelter for Delinquent Boys, 185224 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Manufacturing and Warehouses, 185225 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Monuments and Statuary, 185226 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
      - Buildings-Residences-A - C, 185229 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bartow-Pell Mansion, Pelham Bay Park, 185230 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bathgate, Charles Residence, West Farms, 185231 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Residences-D - F, 185232 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Buildings-Residences-Ferris Houses, 185233 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Buildings-Residences-Fox Estate, 185234 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Buildings-Residences-G - L, 185235 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Buildings-Residences-Hadley House, 185236 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Buildings-Residences-Hunt Mansion, 185237 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Buildings-Residences-Lorillard Mansions and Snuff Mill, 185238 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Buildings-Residences-M - N, 185239 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Morris, Gouverneur Mansion, 185240 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Morris, William H. Mansion and Estate, 185241 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-O - S, 185242 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Poe, Edgar Allen, Cottage, 185243 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Poole, Townsend House, 185244 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-T - V, 185245 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Van Cortlandt Mansion, 185246 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-W - Z, 185247 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Zbrowski (Zabriskie) Mansion, Claremont Park, 185248 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Unidentified, 185249 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Restaurants (A-Z), 185250 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Taverns (A-Z), 185251 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Schools-Primary and Secondary, 185252 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Colleges and Universities (including NYU and Manhattan College), 185254 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
      - Buildings-Sports Stadia-Yankee Stadium, 185257 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations, 185258 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Buildings- Miscellaneous, 185259 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Utilities, 183058
      - Utilities, 185260 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Transportation, 183059
      - Bus and Trolleys, 185261 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Railroads, 185262 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Third Avenue Elevated Railroad, 185263 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Events, 183060
      - Blizzard of Dec. 27, 1947, 185264 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Bronx Borough Day, 185265 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Parades (including firemen), 185267 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
    - Bronx - Boxed Materials - Unidentified photos, 185270 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Subseries IIB: BRONX - FLAT MATERIAL
    - Bronx - Flat Material - Views
      - Aerial Views (Folder FF451)
        includes aerial views of Tremont, the West Bronx, and City Island.
      - General Views - Prints (Folder FF452)
        includes: 1891 auction map of lots for sale in 23rd Ward, near St. Mary's Park
        "A View of Phillip's Manor and the Rocks on the Hudson," from a drawing dated 1784
        "View of Melrose and Surroundings taken from the Ursuline Convent," 1868
        Mott Haven, showing Mott Iron Works
        1896 auction map of lots for sale at Underwood Terrace, Morris Heights, 24th ward
        "Historical Morrisania (Village)," 1861. Three versions, one with color
        "Plan of E.C. Cooper's Patent Inclined Plane Salt Works," City Island, East River, circa 1835
        "Fairmount Atheneum. Lewis Terrace, West Morrisania" undated
        "Car tracks, Cars, and Wagons on Third Avenue, Morrisania...and location of posts for proposed elevated railroad," 1881.
      - General Views - Photos (Folder FF453)
        West Farms Village
        Kingsbridge
        Spuyten Duyvil
        St. Ann's Avenue
        Washington Avenue
        Westchester Avenue
        Throgg's Neck Bridge approach
        unidentified open air theater, Mott Haven
        A. Hupfel's Sons Brewery, St. Ann's Avenue
      - Views - Grand Concourse, 1895-1897 (Folder FF453.5)
        Birds-eye views and street views (prints) produced by the Department of Street Improvements, showing the plans for the construction of the Grand Concourse.
      - Views - Parks and Gardens (Folder FF454)
        Bronx Park, photo by Elwin R. Sanborn, circa 1900
        Macomb's Dam Park, athletic field, circa 1910
        Old Snuff Mill in Bronx Park (now within Bronx Botanical Gardens)
        Van Cortland Mills in Van Cortland Park, photo by Edward Wenzel, 1893
        Van Cortland Mills in Van Cortland Park, unidentified photographer
        Van Cortland's Park, 1st-23rd- 71st Regiments [military encampment], 1917
    - Bronx - Flat Material - Buildings
      - Churches (Folder FF455)
        St. Ann's Protestant Episcopal Church, St. Ann's Avenue ca. 1873
        St. Edmund's Church, 176th Street
        St. Paul's Chapel, St. Ann's Parish, Morrisania
        St. Peter's Church, Westchester Avenue 1879-80
        Ursuline Convent, East Morrisania
        West Farms Reformed Church, Boston Road 1898
      - Clubs and Organizations (Folder FF456)
        Sibberns' Club House, Jerome Avenue
        Tremont YWCA
      - Government Buildings - Firehouses (Folder FF457)
        Independence Engine Co. #1, Williamsbridge
        Lady Washington Engine Co. #1, Fulton St.
      - Government Buildings - Municipal Building (Folder FF458)
        consists of photographs of the Bronx Municipal Building, later called Bronx Borough Hall. It was designed by George Post and completed in 1897. Demolished 1969.
      - Hotels (Folder FF459)
        photographs of Drovers Inn
        Nolans' Hotel
        Thwaite's Homestead Hotel
      - Residences - A-L (Folder FF460)
        Dr. Anderson House, Throgg's Neck, print
        Ashe-Leland-Van Scheck-Mitchell-Huntington House, photo by Nash, 1905
        Bailey, N.P. House, Fordham, two photolithographs
        Bartow House, Pelham Bridge Road, photo by Nash
        Berrian-Johnson House, Spuyten Duyvil Parkway, photo by Nash, 1906
        Bourne, D.B. House, photo by Nash, 1904
        Faile, E.G., "Locusts" House, photo by Nash, 1905
        Faile, E.G., "Woodside" House
        Ferris Houses, three photos by Nash, 1904-05
        Fox-Tiffany House, Westchester Avenue, photo circa 1895.
      - Residences - G-P (Folder FF461)
        Hadley House, Kingsbridge, photo by Nash, 1903
        Horton Farmhouse, City Island, photo by Nash, 1903
        Husted House, 221st Street, photo by Nash, 1903
        Hutchins, Waldo, Kingsbridge, photo by Nash, 1906
        Macomb, Robert House, Kingsbridge, photo by Nash, 1904
        Marshall House, City Island, photo by Nash, 1904
        Mathewson, Douglas House, 2024 Creston Avenue, drawing, circa 1911
        Miller House, Newton Ave, photo by Nash, 1906
        Montgomery Cottage, Fort Independence Avenue, photo by Nash, 1905
        Pell, Joshua House, Pelham, photo by Nash, 1904
        Poe, Edgar Allen, Cottage, photo by Edward Wenzel, 1893
        Poe, Edgar Allen, Cottage, 1902
        Poe, Edgar Allen, Cottage, circa 1910
        Powell Farmhouse, Washington Avenue, photo by Nash, 1904
      - Residences - Q-Z (Folder FF462)
        Randall House, 1323 Franklin Avenue
        Spy House, Morrisania, photo by Nash, 1905
        Stanton House, Washington Avenue, photo by Nash, 1904
        Tippett Mansion, Riverdale Avenue, photo by Nash
        Valentine-Cornell Homestead, photo by Nash, 1903
        Van Cortlandt Manor, 1905
        Varian, Isaac, Van Cortlandt Avenue, photo by Nash, 1901
        Wilkens, Walter House, Prospect Avenue, photo circa 1899
        Wilkins Farmhouse, Unionport, photo by Nash, 1904
        Williams, John House, 215th Street, photo by Nash, 1903
      - Residences - Ellis (Folder FF463)
        interior and exterior views of the home of John Stoneacre Ellis. includes photos of Ellis' collection of European arms and armor.
      - Residences - Morris (Folder FF464)
        various mansions and estates of the Morris family.
      - Residences - Vyse Manor (Folder FF465)
        Vyse family house on their estate called "Rocklands."
      - Residences - Other (Folder FF466)
        photos of houses taken by George W. Nash, 1903-1904.
      - Schools and Colleges (Folder FF467)
        Grammar School #5 (later #64), Webster Avenue 1890
        Fordham University
        Manhattan College (lithograph)
    - Bronx Flat - Material - Events
      - Borough Day Parade, 1915 (Folder FF468)
      - Breaking ground for subway construction, Westchester Avenue, 1916 (Folder FF468)
  - Subseries IIC: BRONX OVERSIZE MATERIAL
    - Birds Eye View of the Proposed Speedway Concourse in Wards 24 and 25 [Bronx], 1892 (Folder *OS FF 523)
      Grand Concourse.
- Series III: New York City Views - Brooklyn, 185271
  Series III New York City Views - Brooklyn is arranged in an organizational structure by topic of the view. GENERAL views include aerial views (those taken from airplanes or from the top of a tall building) and birds-eye views (generally 19th-century prints).
  - Subseries IIIA: BROOKLYN - BOXED MATERIAL
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Aerial Views, 185272
      - Aerial & Bird's Eye Views, 185301 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - General Views, 185273
      - General views, 185302 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Waterfront views (piers), 185303 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Navy Yard, 185304 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Fort Hamilton, 185305 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Fort Lafayette, 185306 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Street Views, 185274
      - Streets-A, 185307 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Atlantic Avenue, 185308 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Streets-B, 185309 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Bedford Avenue, 185310 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Blake Avenue, 185311 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Streets-C, 185312 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Clarkson Avenue, 185313 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Clinton Street, 185314 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Coney Island Avenue, 185315 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Court Street, 185316 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Streets-D, 185317 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Driggs Avenue, 185318 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Dumont Avenue, 185319 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Streets-E, 185320 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - East New York Avenue, 185321 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Streets-F, 185322 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Flatbush Avenue, 185323 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Fulton Street, 185324 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Streets-G, 185325 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Streets-H, 185326 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Humboldt Street, 185327 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Streets-I, 185328 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Streets-J, 185329 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Streets-K, 185330 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Kings Highway, 185331 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Kent Avenue, 185332 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Streets-L, 185333 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Streets-M, 185334 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Manhattan Avenue, 185335 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Metropolitan Avenue, 185336 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Montague Street, 185337 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Streets-N, 185338 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Neck Road (Gravesend Neck Road), 185339 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - New Lots Road, 185340 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Nostrand Avenue, 185341 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Streets-O, 185342 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Ocean Avenue, 185343 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Streets- P-Q, 185344 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Paerdegat Street, 185345 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Pierrepont Street, 185346 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Pitkin Avenue, 185347 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Streets-R, 185452 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Ralph Avenue, 185453 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Rockaway Avenue, 185454 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Rogers Avenue, 185455 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Streets-S, 185456 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Snyder Avenue, 185457 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Sutter Avenue, 185458 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Streets-T, 185459 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Streets-U, 185460 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Streets-V, 185461 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Streets-W, 185462 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Wilson Avenue, 185463 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Wyckoff Street, 185464 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Second Avenue, 185465 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Third Avenue, 185466 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Fifth Avenue, 185467 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Sixth Avenue to Twenty-third Avenue, 185469 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Numbered Streets- 1st to 99th Streets, 185477 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Bay numbered Streets, 185484 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - East Numbered Streets, 185485 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - North Numbered Streets, 185487 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - West Numbered Streets, 185488 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Neighborhoods, 185282
      - Coney Island-Amusement parks, 185493 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Coney Island-Beach and bathers, 185492 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
      - Coney Island-Beach and bathers (5 folders ), 185494 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
      - Coney Island-Mermaid parade, 185500 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Cypress Hill, 185501 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - East New York, 185502 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Flatbush, 185503 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Flatlands, 185504 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Greenpoint, 185505 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Williamsburg, 185506 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Other Neighborhoods, 185507 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Parks/Gardens/Cemeteries, 185283
      - Cemeteries, 185508 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Cemeteries-Greenwood Cemetery, 185509 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Brooklyn Botanic Gardens, 215530 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Fort Greene Park, 215531 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Prospect Park, 185510 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
      - Parks and Playgrounds-misc, 185512 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Buildings, 185284
      - Buildings-Armories, 185513 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Churches & Synagogues-"Houses of Worship," photographs by George Stacy, 185514 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Churches & Synagogues- A-L, 185516 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Churches & Synagogues-Flatbush Dutch Reformed Church, 185515 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Churches & Synagogues-M - Z, 185517 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Churches & Synagogues-Unidentified, 185518 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Clubs and Organizations, 185519 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Commercial buildings, 185521 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Financial institutions, 185520 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Government-General, 185522 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Government-Borough/City Hall, 185523 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Hotels-General, 185524 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Manhattan Beach Hotel, 185525 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Housing Developments, 185526 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Institutions-General, 185527 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-General, 185528 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Wyckoff Memorial Hospital, 185529 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Libraries and Museums, 185530 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Manufacturing and Warehouses, 185531 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-A, 185532 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-B, 185533 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bartlett, H.M., M.D., House, Flatbush Ave. and Fenimore St., 185534 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bergen Homestead, East 72nd St., 185535 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-C, 185536 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-Crooke-Schenck House, Crookes Rd., 185537 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-D-E, 185538 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Residences-F-G, 185539 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-H-K, 185540 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Residences-L, 185650 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Lefferts Homestead, Flatbush Ave. (now in Prospect Park), 185651 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Lott House, East 36th Street, 185652 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-M - N, 185653 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Martense, Judge, House, 676 Flatbush Ave., 185654 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-O - Q, 185655 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-R, 185656 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Rapalje House, 349 New Lots Road, 185657 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Remsen Farmhouse, New Lots Rd. and Church Ave., 185659 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-S, 185660 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Schenck House, Rockaway Ave., 185661 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-Snedeker House, 185662 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-T - V, 185663 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Residences-Van Brunt House, 84th St., 185664 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-Van Buren Homestead, Flatbush Ave, 185665 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Vanderveer House, Flatbush Ave, and mill, 185666 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Van Pelt Manor House, Eighteenth Ave., 185668 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Voorhees House, Neck Rd., 185669 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-W - Z, 185670 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Wyckoff House, Canarsie Ln., 185671 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-Unidentified Residences, 185672 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Schools and Colleges-General, 185673 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Schools and Colleges-Erasmus Hall Academy, 185674 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Schools and Colleges-Midwood High School, 185675 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Schools and Colleges-Packer Collegiate Institute, 185676 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Schools and Colleges-Public School #3, Bedford Ave., 185677 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Sports Stadia-Ebbets Field, 215503 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Theatres, 185678 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Miscellaneous, 185679 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Industry and Utilities, 215578
      - Industry, 185680 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Transportation, 215580
      - Transportation-General, 185681 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Transportation-Fulton Ferry and Ferry House, 185682 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated, 185683 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Transportations-Railroads-Street, 185684 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn - Boxed Material - Events, 215581
      - Events-Blizzard of 1888, 185685 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Events-Blizzard of 1947, 185686 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Events-Miscellaneous, 185687 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IIIB: BROOKLYN - FLAT MATERIAL
    - Brooklyn - Flat Material -Views
      - General Views - Prints (Folder FF469)
        "Sketch of Labon's Inn, Flatbush Avenue, Brooklyn, 1853 taken by A.L. Vanderbilt, city surveyor." Lithograph by G. Hayward
        "Turn Halle in Williamsburgh L.I." printed by F. Wogram, published by F. Schmidt
        "View of Front St. Brooklyn, L.I. 1820," from a painting by Francis Guy. Lithograph by G. Hayward
        "Brooklyn in 1816" from the original painting by F. Guy. Published by E. M. Smith
        "View of Brooklyn, 1840." Lithograph by G. Hayward
        "View from Gowanus Heights (Brooklyn)," published for Herrmann J. Meyer
        "Manhattan Beach," drawn and executed by Galt and Hoy
        "Atlantic Avenue, as proposed to be widened and improved, showing the Drive and Promenade," lithograph of Robertson, Seibert, and Shearman. [2 copies]
        "The Academy of Music, Montague Street, Brooklyn," lithograph of A. Brown and Co.
        "Old Saw-Mill, L.I.," lithographed and published by N. Currier
      - General Views - Prints (Folder FF470)
        "Carnival of the Washington Skating Club, Brooklyn, February 10, 1862," on stone and published by G. E. Jones
        "East New York, N.Y." [two views on one sheet], Chas. Hart, lithographer, published by W. Shapter, 1873
        "North View of the Centre of the Manufacturing District of East New York taken from Pennsylvania Avenue South of the Railroad."
        "East New York, 1867," published by G. Kraetzer
        "View of Brooklyn City Water Works and Cypress Hills from Ridgewood Reservoir," F. Blumner, lithographer, published by G. Kraetzer, 1859